<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Blog</title>
    <link>https://jajeffries.com/blog/pages/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 11:17:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jajeffries.com/blog/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://jajeffries.com/blog/pages/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 11:17:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jajeffries.com/blog/pages/about-me/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a Manchester based software developer with experience in a range of complex fields. I&amp;rsquo;m a polyglot programmer who believes in polyglot persistence. I enjoy working with people to tackle hard problems which make a difference. Got something interesting you want to work on together or want to chat about your project? Fill in the form below or tweet me @jjeffries1 [contact-form subject=&amp;rsquo;[James Jeffries%26#039; Blog&amp;rsquo;][contact-field label=&amp;lsquo;Name&amp;rsquo; type=&amp;lsquo;name&amp;rsquo; required=&amp;lsquo;1&amp;rsquo;/][contact-field label=&amp;lsquo;Email&amp;rsquo; type=&amp;lsquo;email&amp;rsquo; required=&amp;lsquo;1&amp;rsquo;/][contact-field label=&amp;lsquo;Comment&amp;rsquo; type=&amp;lsquo;textarea&amp;rsquo; required=&amp;lsquo;1&amp;rsquo;/][/contact-form]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talks</title>
      <link>https://jajeffries.com/blog/pages/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2013 15:34:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jajeffries.com/blog/pages/talks/</guid>
      <description>From time to time I talk at user groups, conferences or present new ideas to teams at work. This page will list the slides from my talks. There are likely more that I&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten to list, especially since I started helping run XP Manchester as there&amp;rsquo;s too many to count. Python Northwest - Using gradual typing to understand legacy code - Jan 2021 Estimates in Context - Lightning Talk - XP Manchester July 2017 A modern agency: applying lean principles in an agency environment - Lean Startup Manchester - September 2016 Stocks, flows and systems - XP Manchester - May 2016 Running a modern agency - Agile Manchester 2016 Panel Member - DevOops - DevOps Manchester - January 2016 An introduction to network automation - DevOps Manchester - October 2015 Hidden queues - XP Manchester - July 2015 Red, green&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
